http://www.pontarddulais-rfc.co.uk/pages/743a024a-7c0f-4d31-b41b-d07634a5fb0b/gdpr-policy

GDPR Policy
Privacy Notice for members of Pontarddulais RFC Limited
PONTARDDULAIS RFC LIMITED takes your privacy seriously. We are a “controller” of the personal information that you provide to us and this privacy notice sets out how, why and for how long we will use your personal data, as well as who it is shared with. It also explains your legal rights as a data subject and how to exercise them.
What we need from you
When you register as a member of PONTARDDULAIS RFC LIMITED or renew your membership (including if you are registering or renewing on behalf of a young person aged 16 or under), we may ask you for some or all of the following personal information:
Contact details – e.g. name, address, email address and phone number.
Date of birth – to calculate membership category and eligibility for events and courses.
Payment details (where applicable) – bank account number, sort code
If you do not provide us with all of the personal information that we need this may affect our ability to offer you our membership services and benefits.
Why we need your personal information
Contractual purposes
We need to collect our members’ and customers’ personal information so that we can manage your relationship with us. We may use our members’ personal information to:
Provide you with core member services, including confirmation of membership, membership card, end of year renewal.
Set up a Standing Order payment for membership payment
Communication for informing you of any of the following: Meetings (Annual General Meeting and/or Extraordinary General Meeting), organised club activities and events
For Rugby players only register your membership with the Welsh Rugby Union.
Legitimate purposes
We also process our members’ personal information in pursuit of our legitimate interests to:
Provide you with news and updates about the activity of the club, opportunities to get involved in club meetings, training, general meetings or other events.
Raise awareness of the club’s activities by capturing photos, videos, or live streaming at events. We will use this for promotion, education and development purposes.
Respond to and investigate your questions, comments, support needs, complaints, concerns or allegations.
Legal obligations
We are under a legal obligation to process certain personal information relating to our members for the purposes of complying with:
Safeguarding of Vulnerable Groups Act (2006), which requires us to check that our coaches and volunteers are able to undertake regulated work with children and vulnerable adults.
The Equality Act 2010, which requires us to process personal information to make reasonable adjustments where necessary.
Why we need your personal information – equality monitoring
Where applicable, we use aggregated and anonymised reports of our members’ personal information for equality monitoring purposes, enabling us to evaluate and promote equality of opportunity within our sport.
Other uses of your personal information
We may ask you if we can process your personal information for other purposes. Where we do so, we will provide you with an additional privacy notice explaining how we will use your information for these purposes.
Who we share your personal information with
When we register your Playing membership with the Welsh Rugby Union we pass on your personal data and the Welsh Rugby Union become a controller of your personal data. The Welsh Rugby Union provides full details of how it uses your personal data in its own privacy notice (http://www.wru.co.uk/eng/legal.php) and will not use it for any other purpose.
We may be required to share personal information with statutory or regulatory authorities to comply with statutory obligations. Such organisations include the Health & Safety Executive, Disclosure and Barring Service for DBS Checks and South Wales Police for the purposes of safeguarding children and UK Anti-Doping for the purpose of eliminating doping in sport. We may also share personal information with professional and legal advisors for the purpose of obtaining advice.
Third party suppliers with access to members’ personal data
Pontarddulais RFC Limited may also use third party suppliers to provide services. These suppliers may process personal data on our behalf as “processors” and are subject to contractual conditions to only process that personal information under our instructions and protect it.
In the event that we share personal information with external third parties, we only share such information strictly required for the specific purposes and take reasonable steps to ensure recipients shall only process the disclosed personal information in accordance with those purposes. Examples are provided in bullet points below.
HSBC process payment transactions securely on our behalf.
Instructors, coaches and event organisers receive details of training or competition participants.
How we protect your personal information
Your personal information is accessed by our Club Secretary and/or Club Treasurer only for the purposes set out above. It is stored by our club on a Spreadsheet that is “Password Protected”. A paper copy is also kept and is stored securely in a locked Club Safe. With regards to Rugby Playing members, your personal data is transferred to the Welsh Rugby Union by inputting it directly into a password-protected database via the Welsh Rugby Union’s “MYWRU” facility.
How long we keep your personal information
We only keep your personal information for as long as necessary to provide you with membership services. Unless you ask us not to, we will review and delete your personal information where you have not renewed your membership with us for two years.
You have a right to:
Change your communication preferences or restrict the processing of your personal data for specific purposes.
Request that we correct your personal data if you believe it is inaccurate or incomplete.
Access the personal data that we hold about you through a “subject access request”.
Request that we delete your personal information.
You can contact us at Pontarddulais Rugby Football Club, Oakfield Street, Pontarddulais, Swansea, SA4 8LW or by email to secretary@pontarddulais-rfc.co.uk
If you are dissatisfied, you have a right to raise a complaint with the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO) at www.ico.org.uk
Pontarddulais RFC Limited are registered with the ICO (Registration Number ZA499697) which covers data in relation to Employees, Members and Players as well as CCTV for Crime prevention and Staff Monitoring.
PONTARDDULAIS RUGBY CLUB
TEAMS /
Seniors
1st Team
2nd Team
Women
Youth
Juniors
Please wait as the server processes your request. Do not attempt to refresh the page.
